JAIR ALCON

1503 W Centennial Dr., Rogers, AR, 72758 (479) 381-2807

jairalcon@gmail.com

https://github.com/jairalcon

SUMMARY

I have over 6 years of professional photography experience and have a strong passion for front-end technologies and Software development. I recently completed a Front-End Developer Bootcamp at Promineo Tech in pursuit of a junior development position. Some of my short-term goals include developing my coding skills as a front-end junior developer and professional skills. Some of my long-term goals include becoming well-established in a company whose mission and goals resonate with me. Another long-term goal is to become a full-stack developer.

EDUCATION

PROMINEO TECH, Surprise, AZ (May 2022 – October 2022)

• Program: Front End Software Developer

Skills and technologies include JavaScript, ES6, Algorithms, OOP, Design Patterns, Unit Testing, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, AJAX, Responsive Web Design, ReactJS, JSX, NPM, Redux, AWS, and more.

Courses:

1. Introduction to JavaScript (6 Weeks)

Basic programming in JavaScript (ES6) to advanced Object-Oriented concepts, functional programming, design patterns, and unit testing. Version control with Git.

2. Front End Technologies (6 Weeks)

User interface design including HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, and AJAX. Built dynamic, responsive applications using vanilla JavaScript and then JQuery.

3. Web App Design with ReactJS (6 Weeks)

Designed and built dynamic, modular user interfaces using ReactJS. Concepts include everything from basic JSX and components to advanced application development and deploying applications with AWS Elastic Beanstalk.

SOUTHWESTERN ADVENTIST UNIVERSITY, Keene, TX (2006 – 2010)

- Psychology Major; Wellness Minor
- Completed three years of academic coursework toward a Bachelor of Science

BENTONVILLE HIGH SCHOOL, Bentonville, AR (2002 – 2005)

• High School Diploma

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Shutterfly Inc. Lifetouch - Rogers, AR

Photography Supervisor, March 2021 – March 2022

- Interview, hire, help on-board, and train new photography team members on a seasonal basis
- Supervise, coach, and develop photography team's skills through on-site training in schools and weekly feedback
- Responsible for efficient picture day scheduling by ensuring appropriate match of photographer's skills to maximize productivity for key accounts
- Ensure the photography team is assigned their equipment sets on a weekly basis by collaborating with Photography Administrator
- Collaborate with Photography Manager to ensure commitments are fulfilled when photography member(s) callin sick

Maintain inventory of expendable photography supplies and other operational responsibilities

Lead Photographer, September 2017 – March 2021

- Received promotion to Lead Photographer
- Conduct interviews and actively participate in the hiring process
- Assist in tailoring seasonal Lifetouch photography training material
- Conduct training for all Lifetouch photography programs for new and experienced photographers
- Carry-out one-on-one meetings with direct reports to promote professionalism
- Mentor photographers to improve their work towards Lifetouch standards
- Promote a positive culture in accordance with Lifetouch policies
- Reconcile photography teams' company gas cards and mileage logs

Seasonal Photographer, September 2015 – September 2017

- Photograph individuals and various groups, including classroom and sports teams for clients ranging from Pre-Schools to High Schools
- Ensure high-quality customer service to students, teachers, staff, and administrators
- Produce quality portraits in accordance with Lifetouch standards
- Complete and submit paperwork and image DVDs to Lab for processing
- Received 2016 Judges Award of Merit for highest quality photos among the top eight in the company
- Competent in all 6 photography programs offered by Shutterfly Inc. Lifetouch

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Bilingual (fluent in English and seasoned in Spanish)
- Proficient in studio/outdoor photography lighting, Lightroom, and Photoshop RAW editing tools
- Working knowledge of Google Workspace, Microsoft 365, and Slack
- Creative foresight with quick problem-solving skills while maintaining vision for future improvements

REFERENCES

- Kyle Pack,
 - o Shutterfly Lifetouch Sales Professional 501-850-6079, kpack@lifetouch.com
- Tammy Carmical,
 - o Shutterfly Lifetouch Area Photography and Operations Manager 501-425-6658, tcarmical@lifetouch.com
- Philip Martin,
 - o Retired Shutterfly Lifetouch Territory Manager 479-644-4115